Narrator: How to be happier
Happiness is very important for our mental health.
These six tips will help you to be happier, more in control, and stronger in difficult times.
Tip one: Manage your stress levels
Speaker: If you have a lot of stress in your life,
organizing your time better will help you to stay in control.
Plan regular exercise and make time for yourself every day.
Do slow-breathing exercises to help you to relax.
Narrator: Tip two: Enjoy yourself
Speaker: Doing things that you enjoy is very good for you.
Simple activities like watching sports with a friend, having a hot bath,
or meeting friends for coffee can all improve your day.
Doing something that you’re good at, for example, cooking or dancing,
is also a good way not only to enjoy yourself, but also to feel positive about yourself.
Try to avoid things that seem enjoyable at the time, but make you feel worse afterwards,
for example, going to bed very late or eating junk food.
Narrator: Tip three: Boost your self-esteem
Speaker: Self-esteem is the way you feel about yourself.
The best way to improve your self-esteem is to treat yourself the same way
you would treat a good friend, in a positive, but honest, way.
Control negative thoughts.
Don’t say to yourself, ‘You’re so stupid for not getting that job’.
Instead think, ‘Would I say that to my best friend?’.
You probably wouldn’t.
Tell yourself something positive, for example,
‘You’re an intelligent person, you’ll definitely get the next job.’
Narrator: Tip four: Have a healthy lifestyle
Speaker: Make healthy choices.
A balanced diet which includes the main food groups helps your brain and body work efficiently.
Doing moderate exercise releases chemicals in your brain that make you feel happier,
and help you to sleep better, have more energy, and keep your heart healthy.
Choose an exercise that you enjoy.
If it helps, do it with a friend or listen to music.
Narrator: Tip five: Talk to other people
Speaker: Communication is important, whether it’s with a friend,
a family member or even a therapist.
Talking about things and sharing your feelings helps you to release tension.
It also helps to make your relationships stronger, and to connect with people.
Narrator: Tip six: Learn to deal with your problems
Speaker: Resilience is what allows you to cope with life’s ups and downs.
Making something good out of bad times helps you build your resilience.
If you’re going through a difficult time,
try making something creative out of your bad experiences.
Things like writing, painting, or singing can help you to express your worries
and see light at the end of the tunnel.